I don't wanna be a product of my environment.
I want my environment to be a product of me.
Years ago, we had the Church.
That was only a way of saying we had each other.
But now, I don't know. It's a funny thing.
It put hate in your heart.
The Knights of Columbus were real head-breakers.
True guineas.
They took over their piece of the city.
Twenty years after an Irishman couldn't get a fucking job...
...we had the presidency. May he rest in peace.
That's what the niggers don't realize.
If I got one thing against the black chappies, it's this:
No one gives it to you.
You have to take it.
Vin, don't make me have to come down here again for this.
Wort happen again, Mr. C.
Carmers developing into a fine young lady.
You should be proud.
You get your period yet, Carmen?
You Johnny Sullivars kid?
- You live with your grandmother? - Yeah.
Vin, get him a couple loaves of bread, couple half-gallons of milk.
Do you like bologna and cheese? Give him some cold cuts.
Throw some mayo in. You like comic books?
You do good in school?
- Yeah. - That's good. I did too.
They call that a paradox.
Just keep it. Buy yourself some makeup.
You ever wanna earn a little extra money, you come by L Street.
You know where I am on L Street?
Good.
- Good boy. - Thanks.
To you, O Lord, we commend the soul of Alphonsus, your servant.
In the sight of this world, he is now dead.
Forgive whatever sins he committed through human weakness.
- Amen. - The Church wants you in your place.
Kneel, stand, kneel, stand.
If you go for that sort of thing, I don't know what to do for you.
A man makes his own way.
No one gives it to you.
You have to take it.
- James Joyce. - Smart, Colin.
Guineas from the North End, down Providence...
...tried to tell me what to do.
And something maybe happened to them.
Maybe like that:
Jeez. She fell funny.
Francis, you really should see somebody.
When you decide to be something, you can be it.
That's what they don't tell you in the Church.
When I was your age, they would say we could become cops or criminals.
Today what I'm saying to you is this:
When you're facing a loaded gun...
...what's the difference?
That's my boy.
Terminal ballistics is the study of a projectile...
...as it hits a target and the destruction that it causes.
Take, for instance, what you carry, 9 mm hollow-point.
When the hollow-point hits the skull, what happens is it mushrooms.
When it mushrooms it peels back. So you may have six, eight...
...ten little particles of the bullet that are like razor blades...
Sir, yes, sir!
- Tearing their internal organs, their liver, their lungs, their heart...
...bringing tissue, bone, blood, brain matter, and that's called a blowback.
Fuck you. Fucking queers.
Firemen getting pussy for the first time in the history of fire or pussy.
Hey, go save a kitten in a tree, you fucking homos.
Pencils.
Begin.
What are you looking at?
Forget it.
Your father was a janitor, his sors only a cop.
Those fucking firefighters are a bunch of homos.
They are.
So she tells me, "You never finish anything. You finish the police course...
...you get taken care of again, baby." So after graduation, I get a blowjob again.
That's great. Your mother must be a wonderful woman.
Fuck yourself.
Put it this way. You're a black guy in Boston.
You don't need any help from me to be completely fucked.
The Massachusetts State Police has a long tradition of excellence.
Your graduation today solidifies your acceptance...
...into one of the finest law enforcement agencies in our nation.
As the governor of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, I am confident...
...each and every one of you will serve with distinction, honor and integrity.
Congratulations to all our new troopers.
Thank you. You are dismissed.
Sullivan, assigned to plainclothes right out of the gate, congratulations.
- We're going for a beer. You wanna come? - No, I'll catch up with you guys.
School's out.
Thank you, Frank.
You earned it.
No more pencils, no more books.
All right.
This is not the regular police...
...this is the state police. - And fire!
Your training will illustrate the difference.
State police, search warrant! State police, open the door!
What's the difference?
- Go, go, go! - Sir, yes, sir!
- Is that understood? - Sir, yes, sir!
Move it, get the fuck down right now. Get down, right now.
Congratulations on passing the detective's exam, and welcome...
...to the Special Investigation Unit. - Whoop-de-fucking-do.
We won't be working together, that is, directly.
You'll be working for Captain Ellerby, but I like to see everybody.
You're a worker. You rise fast.
Like a 12-year-old's dick.
- Thank you, sergeant. - My pleasure.
- Thank you, sir. - Good luck.
- Congratulations. - Thanks, hon.
You can go in there now.
You can sit.
So...
Do you know what we do here? My section?
- Yes, sir, I have an idea... - Let's say you have no idea...
...and leave it at that, okay?
No idea. Zip. None.
If you had an idea what we do, we would not be good at what we do, would we?
We would be cunts.
Are you calling us cunts?
Staff Sergeant Dignam has a style of his own.
I'm afraid we all have to get used to it.
So you have family connections down in Southie, right? Through your father?
Why don't you tell us about your Uncle Jackie?
He was a carpet layer for Jordan Marsh.
Uncle Jackie was a small-time bookie who tended bar at the Vets in Somerville.
He got popped by Nicastro in '95. We found his body out by the airport.
That's right.
- I remember his funeral. - Oh, good.
Closed casket?
That's right.
So tell anybody up at Deerfield...
Before you got kicked out for whaling on a gym teacher with a chair.
- You had an uncle met his demise like that?
I got a question.
How fucked up are you?
Hi, Darlene.
What you got, staff sergeant? In no time you made sergeant.
- SIU. What a country. - Perfect.
Hey, I don't mind going it alone.
You know, if you went alone once in a while you might get somewhere.
We're cops, all right? This isn't somewhere.
All right, lookit, I know you're a worker. Maybe I can do something for you.
You got any suits, or do you like...
...coming to work dressed like you're gonna invade Poland?
You got quite the family tree. That maggot uncle of yours...
...Tommy Costigan, is another goof. He gets busted selling guns...
...to federal officers, among many, many, many other departures...
...from our normative behavior. - And what's this got to do with me?
Why are you pretending to be a cop?
This unit is new, and you are the newest members of it.
You have been selected for it on the basis of intelligence and aptitude.
This is an elite unit.
Our job is to smash or marginally disrupt...
...organized crime in this city...
...by enanced cooperation with the FBI...
...represented here today by Agent Frank Lazio.
And we will do it.
And by organized crime in this city, you know who we mean.
That's Jackie Costigan. That's an old picture.
Jackie met his demise.
Last known photograph.
Costello uses three key guys.
That's Fitzy. Off-the-boat psycho, lives in Brockton with his mother.
She's straight out of Going My Way.
Delahunt, muscle.
French, the number one. But of course, the rock star, you-know-who.
We've done a briefing book, so read up. I want all ideas...
...so I can pass them off as my own.
Work hard, you'll rise fast. You're in the best possible position...
...in the department. Let's go to work.
Your old man was a fucking hump from Southie.
Baggage handler at the airport, right?
Family's all criminals except for the old man, huh?
And one priest, since you seem to know everything.
Last I heard he was married to a 12-year-old boy, living on a beach in Thailand.
Fucking family's dug into the Southie projects like ticks.
Three-decker men at best. You, however, grew up...
...on the North Shore, huh? Well, la-di-fucking-da.
You were kind of a double kid, I bet, right?
One kid with your old man, one kid with your mother.
You're upper-middle class during the weeks, then you're hanging...
...in the Southie projects with your daddy, the fucking donkey...
...on the weekends. I got that right?
Yup. You have different accents?
You did, didn't you, you little fucking snake?
- You were like different people. - You a psychiatrist?
If I was, I'd ask you why you're a statie making 30 grand a year.
And I think if I was Sigmund fucking Freud I wouldn't get an answer.
Tell me, what's a lace-curtain motherfucker like you doing in the staties?
Well, families are always rising or falling in America, am I right?
- Who said that? - Hawthorne.
What's the matter, smart-ass, you don't know any fucking Shakespeare?
We have a question.
Do you wanna be a cop, or do you wanna appear to be a cop?
It's an honest question.
Lot of guys want to appear to be cops. Gun, badge, pretend they're on TV.
A lot of them just wanna slam a nigger through a window...
I'm set without your own personal job application, sergeant.
- What did you say? - Sir, what do you want from me?
Hey, he can't help you.
I know what you are. I know what you are...
...and I know what you're not.
I'm the best friend you have and I'm gonna help you understand something.
You're no fucking cop.
He's right. We deal in deception here.
What we do not deal with is self-deception.
Five years from now you could be anything else in the world.
But you will not be a Massachusetts state trooper.
- Are you sure of that? - I'm sure of that.
Guaran-fucking-teed.
You had 1400 on your SATs, kid. You're an astronaut, not a statie.
You don't have much family.
I don't have any family.
What's this I hear from Stephanie about you becoming a policeman?
Stephanie, who was the only one who came to my father's funeral?
- That Stephanie? - Yeah, that Stephanie.
- Nothing much to it, Uncle Edward. - Trying to prove something to the family?
When you say "the family," who do you mean exactly? You?
You always have to question everything, don't you?
Maybe it would've done you some good to have some questions from time to time.
"Am I an asshole? Are my kids a mess?
Is my wife a money-grubbing whore?" I mean, those are questions, right?
"Have I ever been good to my dying sister, or am I just now pretending to be?"
Do you need some money for the funeral?
When my mother dies, we don't have any more connection.
It's lovely. You get the high ceilings, the parquet floors. Bathroom is massive.
The fridge has got an alarm in it in case you have...
...eating issues, which is a joke. Not a very funny one.
Well, there's a great view of the State House. Beacon Hill, you can see it.
I mean, you move in, you're upper-class by about Tuesday.
- So you're a cop. - A state-police detective.
A state-police detective.
And are you a married state-police detective?
No.
Because this is kind of a... Sort of a big place and...
I have a co-signer.
Oh, cool. Yeah, you intend to have a houseguest. That's cool. Good.
- Yeah, it's got... - Just give me the papers.
Sure.
Eternal rest grant unto her, O Lord, and let perpetual light shine upon her.
- Amen. - May she rest in peace. Amen.
May her soul and the souls of all the faithful departed...
...through the mercy of God rest in peace.
Amen.
天堂收留虔诚的逝者，弗兰克·卡斯特罗
So what do I do?
There's money behind this operation. You won't be paid as a regular cop...
...but there's a bonus involved.
Tax-free.
We can't conceal that you were a trainee. You'll be convicted of a crime.
We're thinking a guilty plea to assault and battery would make sense.
Given your nature.
You'll do enough jail time to convince anyone this is no setup.
You'll be on probation, see a court-ordered shrink...
...the whole nine yards.
You wanna serve the Commonwealth, this is your chance.
We need you, pal.
You've already pretended to be a Costigan from South Boston.
- Every weekend, sergeant. - Perfect.
Do it again.
For me.
无间行者
- Hey, you Billy Costigan? - Yeah, who wants to know?
Well, nothing. I know a Sean Costigan down on L Street.
- Yeah, that's my cousin. - Connected. Not too bright.
- Yeah, I know. - I mean, no offense.
- Billy? - Yeah, it's me.
- Oh, my God. Good to see you. - Aunt Kathy, how are you?
Oh, good to see you. Come on in.
They said you was in the staties. I couldn't believe it.
I got kicked out, like, four months ago.
Yeah, it was in the papers.
So you know.
And why are we graced with your presence?
I brought your mother some pictures of my father.
- Look at the smile. - My mother had them. My...
My mother's dead.
I'm sorry. Sorry for your troubles.
I was at a funeral myself, man.
Myles Kennefick. Knew him in school.
He was a young guy, you know? It's terrible. It's a shame.
- You remember that. What a night. - Listen.
I got, like...
- Like 30,000 bucks, right? Insurance money. - Yeah.
You know, after my mother passed and everything.
In your line of work, if I gave you...
...like, what, say, 10,000, what could I get back?
You know what you...
You know what you usually say at these moments.
- What? What? - Come on, man.
Oh, come on, you fucking moron. Come on.
What, you want me to say it?
I'm not a cop, all right?
- I'm your fucking cousin. - You're bad.
You corrupt fuck, man. You must be my cousin.
Fucking Ricans think they know everything.
If they knew shit, they wouldn't be Puerto Ricans.
R is for Ricans P is for pigs
Would you shut the fuck up for five seconds, huh?
That's right. You used to be a cop.
When we're working together just limit it to two eight-balls an hour.
We're not even supposed to be doing this shit this close to Worcester.
This side of Worcester.
- Says who? - Says him. Says Costello.
God says, as far as you're...
...concerned.
No, no, he's no cop. He got out of the joint three weeks ago.
- Cunt cop. - No, no, no.
He talks like his shit don't stink, but he's good people.
Well, I knew his father.
- I liked his Uncle Jackie better. - Jackie was all right.
Uncle Jackie was excellent.
Fucking guineas.
- To Jackie. - Uncle Jackie.
Cranberry juice.
It's a natural diuretic.
My girlfriend drinks it when she's got her period.
What, do you got your period?
- Fucking...! - Get off!
- Get your fucking hands off me! - Hey. Hey, hey.
Do you know me?
No. No.
Well, I'm the guy that tells you there are guys you can hit...
...and there's guys you can't.
Now, that's not quite a guy you can't hit...
...but it's almost a guy you can't hit.
So I'm gonna make a fucking ruling on this right now:
You don't fucking hit him. You understand?
Yeah, excellent. Fine. Fine, fine.
I fucking know you. I know your family.
You make one more drug deal...
...with that idiot fucking cop-magnet of a cousin of yours...
...and I'll forget your grandmother was so nice to me.
I'll cut your fucking nuts off. You understand that?
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
What are you drinking?
A cranberry juice.
What is it, your period?
Get him a cranberry juice.
Hey, fuckhead, that's Jackie's nephew.
What? "Oh," fucking what?
Get the fuck out of here.
Sorry I'm late.
Staff Sergeant Dignam is our liaison to the undercover section.
His undercover work is extensive.
He's here to give us his report. Sergeant Dignam.
Okay, my people are out there.
They're like fucking Indians. You're not gonna see them.
You'll hear about them through me or Captain Queenan.
You will not ever know the identity of undercover people.
Unfortunately, this shithole has more leaks than the Iraqi navy.
- Fuck yourself. - I'm tired from fucking your wife.
- How's your mother? - Tired from fucking my father.
Good. Today, girls...
...what I have is microprocessors.
Somebody, as you may already know, stole 20 microprocessors...
...from the Mass Processor Company out on Route 128.
These are the kind they put into computers...
...that could put a cruise missile up the ass of a camel...
...from a couple hundred miles away.
These pieces of plastic are won'th about 100 grand apiece.
We got a guy working for the company two months...
...walks out the door with a box of processors on Tuesday...
...has a ticket for Florida on Wednesday...
...but on Thursday, he gets found in a Dumpster.
You know where that dirtball started his life?
Southie projects.
- What was his name, the departed? - Myles Kennefick.
Got the job with a forged UMass transcript. UMass, Boston...
...which happens to... - South Boston?
Oh, you're a fucking genius. Who forged your transcript, dickhead?
His old man runs the Hibernian Liquor Mart. Kennefick's.
We're not here to solve the case of the missing scumbag.
We're here to nail Costello.
All right, look. We got a guy...
...says Costello's moving the processors to China.
He set up the whole fucking job and popped Kennefick.
You do not want to miss it if Costello takes a dump.
We'd miss less if you made your informants available to us and the Bureau.
Without asking for too many details, do you have anyone in with Costello now?
Maybe. Maybe not.
Maybe fuck yourself.
My theory on Feds is they're like mushrooms.
Feed them shit and keep them in the dark.
You girls have a good day.
Normally he's a very nice guy.
Don't judge him from this meeting alone.
Now, Mrs. Kennefick, I knew your son.
I knew Myles.
He was younger than me, but he was behind me in school.
I wanna get these people who did this to him.
Would you like to help us? You wanna help catch the people...
...who forced your son to do a robbery and then killed him?
Allegedly.
If he was killed, he probably did something wrong.
But not the robbery. That's not wrong.
He did something else wrong?
Wave to your girlfriend, honey.
I mean, fuck yourself.
- Did you get that? - "Allegedly" or "fuck yourself"?
- Welcome to the neighborhood. - Different breed down here, sarge.
I need a cup of coffee.
You making a house call?
Have I seen you professionally?
No, no. No, I know who you are, though. I know.
Guys gotta use their service revolver in the course of duty...
...and then they get to come to talk to you about their feelings and whatnot.
No, no, I know how it goes. You're a mental health professional.
I have an appointment on this floor.
Oh, well, you'll have fun. They're all frigging crazy on that floor.
- I'm one more up. - Oh, fancy policeman.
- Yeah, that's right, fancy. - Are you a statie?
Yeah, I am. I'm actually going to law school also.
Suffolk, nights?
Yeah, they don't run Harvard at night, last time I checked.
- Whers the last time you checked? - Before I went to fucking Suffolk.
Okay, listen, I went to UMass. I wasrt insulting you.
Well, I thought you were. So now you gotta buy me dinner.
Maybe you can shoot someone and then see me professionally.
I'll stab someone in the heart with a fucking ice pick if it gets me dinner with you.
That's all right. I'm a detective. I'll find you.
No, sorry. I'm just joking. I need the card. Card helps.
Nice to meet you, Madolyn.
Hi, Dad. I had no idea about the tail until I saw it.
No, I couldn't. I had the other guy with me, I couldn't...
All right, it's a blue sedan and then a white van.
It's fucked up with graffiti. And the van is the audio surveillance.
All right, have a nice day.
Cut him here.
Bye-bye.
Jerk-ass!
Come on, Babu. I can't do anymore. I cannot hold off.
Don't let me go back empty-handed. Don't do this. I wanna help you.
Come to my store next Friday. I'll give you the money.
This is Friday, Babu. How many times I gotta tell you?
You keep on calling me Babu. It's Singh, motherfucker.
I'm trying to help you.
You keep telling me I'm your friend. You don't even know my fucking name.
I'm gonna catch a beating if I go back again like last week.
See this guy? You see this guy? This guy don't want you to have the money.
Because he wants to come back there and squash your head.
I have one customer sitting here. What I'm gonna do?
Business is bad? You opened a store in an Irish neighborhood.
These are dirty people. Don't you know that?
Sell potatoes, I don't know what you're gonna do.
- Excuse me, gentlemen. Excuse me. Sorry. - Know what I'm saying?
You fellas come from Providence?
It isn't any of your business, is it, now?
What, are you fucking delivering cannolis or something?
Hey! You are killing my business, man!
Fuck!
What's wrong with this fucking country? Everybody hates everybody!
Get out of here. Get out of here!
- Now, you also do probation work, right? - That's right, I see violent offenders.
- Oh, bad guys. - Not necessarily.
Yeah, they got this but they don't got duck I'orange.
Was your meal okay?
Yeah, no, the lobster was good.
I just, you know, because it was a French restaurant I was surprised.
I'm waiting for you to make your move.
Look, I don't know, if that thing moves, I'm gonna shoot it.
I don't even know what it is.
So what's it like having people find themselves...
...in your office all day long?
Does it get messy with all those feelings flying around?
Why, does that make you uncomfortable?
- No, no, no. - No?
No, no, no. No, I'm not on your couch.
Well, you know what Freud said about the Irish?
Yeah, I do.
Yeah, if you actually do, I'll see you again.
Who says I wanna see you again?
Don't you?
- You should see your face. - Don't you?
Course I wanna see you again.
What Freud said about the Irish is...
...we're the only people who are impervious to psychoanalysis.
- Yeah, he said that. - I know he did.
So you're up shit's creek with a client list full of mick cops.
I mean, opening up? Good luck to you.
Why do you do it, then?
Some people do get better.
Fair enough.
Sometimes I want people to forget their personal bullshit and do their jobs.
Including the criminals?
If they don't do their jobs, you don't have one.
I'll always have a job. I'll just arrest innocent people.
- Wait. You are trouble. - You don't know the half of it.
I'll arrest you right now.
My word against yours.
- Then I see her dancing at the wedding with you-know-who.
I say, "Why don't you go to Parents Without Partners?"
He goes, "Ma, they're all losers at the Parents Without Partners," so...
So I say to him, "Princess Carolina of Monaco..."
Schuyler.
Do you know who I am?
No.
You met my friend Mr. French the other night.
His real name Mr. French?
No.
Come with me.
I'm not the cops. I'm not asking you.
You know something, they just do not stop having the Mafia in Providence.
And this can cause me a lot of problems.
Those guys you tuned up...
...they're connected down Providence.
What they're gonna do...
...is come back with some guys and kill you.
Which, sure as you're born, they will do.
Unless I stop them.
Do you want me to stop them?
Is this something I can't do personally?
I'm gonna have my associate search you.
No one's searching me. Search me for what?
Contra-fucking-band. Take your shoes off.
Shoes.
I knew your father.
Yeah? Do you know he's dead?
Oh, sorry. How'd he go?
- Stand. - He didn't complain.
Yeah, that was his problem.
Who said he had a problem?
I just said he had a fucking problem.
There's a man could've been anything.
Are you trying to say that he was nothing?
- Fuck. - I'm saying he worked at the airport.
- He's clean. - Arm.
Yeah, come on.
What arm? What fucking arm?
Show me your arm. Flip it.
Makes me curious to see you in this neighborhood.
He's clean.
And if I can slander my own environment...
...it makes me sad, this regression.
Plus, I don't know if it's beyond some fucking cop prick like Queenan...
...to pull you out of the staties and send you after me.
I just can't know.
I don't know what they do in that particular department, anyway.
- Are you still a cop? - No! No!
Swear on your mother's grave you're still not a cop?
I am not a fucking cop!
Are you gonna stop doing coke deals with your jerkoff fucking cousin?
Yes. Yes, yes.
All right, all right, all right.
You're okay. You'll be all right.
Get your hand taken care of.
I'm sorry, but it was necessary.
As for our problem with Providence...
...let's not cry over spilled guineas.
Who let this IRA motherfucker in my bar?
Just kidding. How's your mother?
She's on her way out.
We all are. Act accordingly.
Here it is, Your Highness, as ordered.
Get in the car. I wanna show you something.
- What's got you all hot and bothered? - Get in the car. You'll see.
Do you trust him?
Well, these days...
...who's reliable?
His Uncle Jackie was.
Yeah, but you can't trust a guy acts like he's got nothing to lose.
I'm reliable.
Arnold, you're one in a million.
Ten. Ten million.
What about your wife, Arnold?
Well, I thought she was.
She wasrt.
Well, she got reliable.
Don't you people ever shut the fuck up?
Another county heard from.
One too many. She got a big mouth.
Answer this for me, will you?
他们闪亮的发丝
我爱那美丽的手指
亲爱的母亲
The principles of detection tell me these two gentlemen came from Providence.
Lieutenant Risteen, Lynn PD. I'd appreciate it you get out of my crime scene.
Yeah, actually, it's my crime scene, but knock yourself out.
Thanks.
I saw a dead guy. I think I'm having posttraumatic stress.
Can I meet you for lunch?
All right, see you then.
Who's the lead detective?
Good. He's a lox.
Get the cops to look at Jimmy Pappas for the hit. He had nothing to do with it...
...and he'll say so.
Look in his car, you'll find the gun that did it, registered, official. Providence.
In the trunk or the glove compartment?
Hey, you wanna see some dead guys?
Hey, this will get Captain Ellerby on the 6:00 news.
No wonder you get ahead.
Have a seat, Bill.
Do you know John Lennon?
Yeah, sure, he was the president before Lincoln.
Lennon said:
"I'm an artist.
You give me a fucking tuba, I'll get you something out of it."
I tell you, Mr. Costello...
...I'd like to squeeze some fucking money out of it.
Smart-mouth.
Too bad.
If you'll indulge me...
Now what?
Choir practice.
Choir practice...
The point I'm making with John Lennon is...
...a man could look at anything...
...and make something out of it.
For instance...
...I look at you and I think:
What could I use you for?
Get rid of this.
French.
Put it downstairs. Here. Go ahead, thank you.
Maybe we could work something out.
- Good. - And send this to his wife.
It was nice the way you asked the guy...
...which hand he jerked off with.
I hope this don't shake Rita up.
As I remember, she ain't that sentimental.
That was quick. You think he's dead already?
We have to do it by phone. I won't do it...
...if I have to wear a wire. No wires. Understand?
- You don't know what this is like. - Microprocessors.
- Micro what? - Microprocessors.
We'll probably be at war with the Chinese in 20-odd years...
...and Costello is selling them military technology.
Microprocessors, chips, computer parts.
Anybody says anything about anything like that...
...you let us know.
So who did the two guys from Providence?
Jimmy Pappas.
What happened to Jimmy Pappas?
Jimmy had a rough month.
Jimmy had a heart attack in jail...
...and then he got himself knifed at Boston City Hospital.
I believe it's been in the papers.
You seem quite happy with that result.
It's a fucking result.
Yeah, but cui bono? Who benefits?
Cui gives a shit? It's got a frigging bow on it.
I think you are a cop, my son.
- Where's your license? - What license?
I don't see none. There's no such thing as a license, of course.
But you, you definitely need to have fucking one.
If you're not being run by us, you're being run by someone else.
That means you're bringing undesirable elements...
...into Mr. Costello's area.
I was going for my fucking cigarettes!
Hey.
That's Jimmy Bags.
- He was rea... I don't know. - What the fuck you doing?
I'm in the hole, I pay him two grand.
There's no profit, I pay him two grand.
Then make more money. This is America.
You don't make money, you're a douche bag. Now what you gonna do?
- Make more money. - That's the spirit!
- Oh, fuck. - Don't worry about it.
The guy don't need any fucking teeth anyway.
It's a small surveillance subunit, but it's mine.
I didn't take this job to fuck up or let anyone else fuck up.
I handpicked this group. You're my A team. Now, our prim...
Hi, Captain.
This crazy fuck...
...knocked Jimmy Bags' teeth out. - So?
- He was... - He was reaching for his cigarettes.
You're gonna give me shit? It wasrt for no reason, Frank.
He reached into his coat.
I don't know if he's a bookie or what he's doing.
Well, you do know what a bookie does, don't you?
Yeah. Yeah, he pays you.
Queenars compartmentalizing everything in SIU...
...which is the right thing.
I don't trust half the troopers out there anymore.
Bottom line...
...we think we might have a problem.
We think Costello's got a rat in the state police.
- Really? - Yeah, really.
Do we have direct access to Queenars undercovers?
No, no, not presently.
But I'm working on that.
Here, Bill, this is for you.
From now on, call the bar, ask for Mikey. Just Mikey.
You ask for Mikey because there is no Mikey.
You wait. We'll call you.
- You got that? - Yeah, I got that.
- Sorry, I didn't hear you. - I got that.
Good.
Hi, Dad.
I got promoted. All right.
Excuse me for one second.
You know...
...if your father were alive...
...and saw you here sitting with me...
...let's say he'd have a word with me about this.
In fact, he'd kill seven guys just to cut my throat.
And he could do it...
...which is maybe something you don't know about William Costigan Sr.
- So he never...? I mean, never? - No. No, no.
He kept his own counsel. He never wanted money.
You can't do anything with a man like that.
Your Uncle Jackie...
...he also would kill my entire fucking family if he saw me here with you.
And I think about this.
So what the fuck are we talking about here?
Did you ever think about going back to school?
School?
With all due respect, Mr. Costello...
...school is out.
Maybe someday you'll wake the fuck up.
Good day, Fathers.
- Mr. Costello. - Good morning, Francis, good morning.
You recall our chat?
Little boys...
...sucking on their peckers, et cetera and so forth...
"I am as God made me." Was that your rationale?
May I remind you, in this archdiocese, God don't run the bingo.
May I remind you that pride comes before the fall.
How's Sister Mary Theresa doing?
We had a tasty relationship before she took her vows.
Enjoy your clams, cocksuckers.
Pay them.
Get the old bombardier a drink on the house.
- What do you got for me? - Uniform clipped him for suspended license.
However, he's a subject of an open investigation...
More than one. He's one of Costello's.
We're getting a warrant. Can't get an address off him.
He paged his lawyer but the lawyer hasn't called back yet.
- Who's the lawyer? - Didrt know the name. Just a number.
Beeper number.
- And the guy didn't show up? - No.
- And he beeped him? - Twice.
Give me your phone. Turn that off.
- What? - Turn the fucking camera off.
Give it to me. He doesn't know what the fucking lawyer looks like.
Whose briefcase is this? All right.
- It's off? - You're good.
Afternoon, Mr. Fitzgibbons.
- He can't do that. - He just did.
- You my attorney? - What do you think?
Have you made statements or phone calls...
...I need to be made aware of?
I beeped you.
The card they gave me. That's it.
- That's it? - That's it.
You need to call your mother...
...tell her you're not gonna be home for supper.
Camera's off. It's off. Call your mother.
Lookit, they're suiting up for a raid right now.
I don't know where they're going, but they do. And so do you.
So make the call.
Lookit, fuckstick, you don't gotta trust me...
...just listen to what I'm saying to you.
Mom, I'm not gonna make it home for supper.
Sorry, yeah, I got held up.
Yeah, no, you carry on without me.
I'll talk to you later. Okay.
Bye.
Everybody out. Move.
Thank you.
So who are you?
I think you need a different attorney, Mr. Fitzgibbons. Have a great day.
So when the fuck am I gonna get out?
All right, run the last number he called. That's his house.
I'll swear to the judge I surveilled him there...
...and abra-fucking-cadabra, we got a warrant.
- Why did you use my phone? - Because you didn't go in there.
The light's nice here in the morning.
So do you wanna talk about last night?
You know, it's all right. Guys tend to make too big a deal out of it.
It's actually quite common.
I gotta go to work.
Do you lie?
Why? Do you?
No, I'm asking if you lie.
Honesty is not synonymous with truth.
Yeah, you lie.
You lie.
Is it to do some good, to get somewhere personally...
...or, what, just for the fuck of it?
Well, I expect that some people do it to keep things on an even keel.
So you had a parent who was a drunk.
Did you?
No.
Let's keep it with you.
Talk about how you feel.
How I feel.
- Fuck. - Brian, stop it.
No. Please. No.
Ain't gonna hurt you.
You sit there...
...with a mass murderer.
A mass murderer.
Your heart rate is jacked.
And your hand...
...steady.
That's one thing I figured out about myself in prison. My hand...
...does not shake.
Ever.
Wake the fuck up.
There was a cop leaving when I came in.
How did you know he was a cop?
Bad haircut, no dress sense and a slight, you know, air of scumbag entitlement.
- Do you see cops? - That's part of what I do.
I normally don't see cadets who've been kicked out of the academy.
Oh, boy. You should get a better job, huh?
Should I?
So do they all come in here...
...and cry, your cops?
Sometimes they do. Yeah, sure. Sometimes they cry, yeah.
If they've had trouble at home, if they've had to use their weapons...
Use their weapons?
Let me tell you something.
They signed up to use their weapons.
Most of them, all right. But they watch enough TV...
...so they know they have to weep after they use their weapons.
There is no one more full of shit than a cop.
Except for a cop on TV.
强力止痛药
I looked at your file.
I see that you have a record of assault.
Yeah.
So what was it like for you in jail?
What, you wanna hear about the showers? Is that what you wanna hear about?
Did something happen to you?
No.
- Okay, let's do this. Come on, spread them. - Hey, you think you can pop somebody...
...and there's a special card to play? Jimmy Bags, whose jaw you broke...
...happens to work undercover for the Boston Police Department.
I'm going nuts. I can't be someone else every day.
It's been a year. I've had enough!
Calm down. Most people do it every day. What's the big deal?
- Well, I'm not them. I'm not them, okay? - Exactly.
You're nobody. You signed the papers, remember?
We're the only two people on this earth that even know you're a cop.
How about we just erase your file, huh?
How about we erase your file...
...and you're just another soldier for Costello...
...open to arrest for I don't know how many felonies. What do you say?
How about I fucking kill you, huh? How about I fucking kill you!
- That was a joke. Come on. - That wasrt a joke.
You play a tough guy, doesn't mean you are one...
...you lace-curtain, Irish fucking pussy! - Hey, hey! Stop it! Break it up! Stop it!
- Fuck you, motherfucker! - Goddamn it, stop it! That's an order!
For chrissake, be smart.
If anybody's watching us now, how are we not supposed to arrest you?
Come on, get in the car.
Both of you, get in the car.
When are you gonna take Costello?
What's wrong with taking him on any one...
...of the million felonies that you've seen him do or I've seen him do?
I mean, he murdered somebody, right?
The guy fucking murders somebody and you don't fucking take him!
What are you waiting for? Do you want him to chop me up and feed me to the poor?
- That what you want? - That'd stick.
Will you shut up?
We are building a case and it takes time.
You know that.
Something's wrong.
I'm telling you, something's wrong.
Yeah, maybe.
Look, we need you to keep your ears open, all right?
No bullshit.
I think Costello's got a spy inside the Special Investigation Unit.
You serious?
I'm afraid so.
Have you heard anything like that?
Jesus Christ.
Hang tight for me, kid.
Just a little while longer.
We are this close:
All right?
What do you expect coming in here?
- I have to come here. - I know you have to come here.
But now that you're here...
...what do you want?
You want the truth?
Valium.
If you lied, you would have an easier time getting what you wanted.
- What's that say about what you do? - We should have a few more meetings...
...before we even talk about prescriptions. - Look, I'm having panic attacks.
Other night, I thought I was having a heart attack. I puked in a barrel on the way over.
I haven't slept for fucking weeks.
- Is that true? - Yeah, that's true.
I said something fucking true. I want some fucking pills...
...and you're gonna close my file?
- I didn't say I'd close your file. No, l... - I thought I was supposed to tell...
...the truth here, if only fucking here. - You are! Yes.
A guy comes in here against every instinct of privacy, of self-reliance that he has...
...and what do you do?
What do you do? You send him off on the street to score smack? Is that what you do?
You're fucking ridiculous.
Two pills?
Why don't you just give me a bottle of Scotch...
...and a handgun to blow my fucking head off?
- Are we done with this psychiatry bullshit? - You can leave!
What did I just put myself through? I'm out of here.
And what if that was a legitimate threat? Think about it, fucking hotshot.
Fuck.
Why is the last patient of the day always the hardest one?
You're tired and you don't give a shit.
- It's not supernatural. - Listen.
Listen. You know, I'm not just somebody that you have to see or they put you in jail.
Okay? I mean, if you're in distress, I will help you.
What's this?
It's my card. And a prescription for 20 lorazepam.
Yeah?
Is it enough to commit suicide?
Maybe it is. All right? Okay?
Have I done my job up to your goddamn standards?
Because according to my standards, you fit the model of drug-seeking behavior.
You know, and too damn bad if you don't like my initial clinical reaction.
Thank you.
I'm transferring you to another counselor.
- Good. - Okay.
So you wanna get a cup of coffee?
Bring it in here, please. Would somebody bring it in?
Come on in.
Our target is a major transaction of microprocessors.
Yes, those.
I don't know what they are, you don't know what they are. Who gives a fuck. Cash.
Lots of cash is gonna change hands inside a building...
...that we have under AV surveillance close-by.
I know this location is not the best, but we had very little time to set up.
- You guys know anything about this? - No.
Sullivars team will ID the bad guys and listen in on the phones.
Our unit will not take action.
I repeat, not take action, until a man that Captain Queenan has inside...
...verifies the transaction. Are we clear?
Anybody? Any questions? No? This is who we're after.
We've been after this cocksucker for a long time, and tonight...
...we are going to get him. Let's go to work.
All right, you guys find out what we're doing and get on it.
Sorry to get you last-minute, but things leak.
This lead came from Queenars undercover guy.
I'm gonna smoke. You don't smoke? One of those fitness freaks, huh? Go fuck yourself.
- Hi, Dad? - Yes.
Yeah, something big came up at work.
- I'm not gonna be home for supper. - Too bad.
Your mother worked all goddamn day.
We'll just have to sit down without you and your friends.
Oh, no, my friends are still coming.
So we'll just... I'll just see you for lunch instead tomorrow.
Your mother will be proud.
All right, thanks, Pop. Bye.
The readiness is all.
You know the players. Call the game.
Thank you.
- You ready? - Is your highness...
...gonna drop me off at confession before work, or fuck me, or what?
What have you got to confess to that anointed pederast?
A confessional seal, these days...
...I'm not so sure.
He'll operate the cameras. You ID the guys and log them.
All cell-phone signals are under surveillance...
...through the courtesy of our federal friends over there.
Patriot Act, Patriot Act. I love it, I love it, I love it.
Keep an eye on this one.
别用电话
发送
All right, here we go.
There's Costello. Mr. French.
There's Fitzy, Delahunt...
...and the new guy, Billy Costigan.
别用电话
Time is 10:46.
All right, turn off your cell phones.
Fitzy's got the chicken. Check your weapons.
- We have a blind spot. - Why do we have a blind spot?
We had two hours' notice. Two hours.
- Fuck you think this is, NASA? - It never crossed my mind.
- Have you got a camera in the back? - What back?
- How you going, Robert? - Good, Mr. Costello.
I wanna tell you, at least two of these gents have machine guns.
有没有搞错啊
我左等右等你都不来
我都想走了
这位先生是政府的人啊，老大
如果被人捉到，他就死定了
是不是都给人杀死才好啊，大哥
He's from the Chinese government. He's scared shitless.
Government man. Scared.
I'm concerned about a Chinaman who thinks it's wise...
...to come to a business transaction...with automatic weapons.
For his own good, tell Bruce Lee and the Karate Kids...
...none of us are carrying automatic weapons.
Because here, in this country...
...it don't add inches to your dick.
You get a life sentence for it.
快点把机关枪收起来
快点收起来
收枪
把枪放下
If we had some Homeland Security money like some douche bags I could mention...
- Any calls? - They turned off their cell phones.
Search randomly for calls made from the area.
Eight hundred and seven phones are live in this area.
Then narrow the area.
What you see there for service is what you're gonna get.
Why did they turn their phones off?
- Wait. There's still one phone up. - Where?
The buyers are there.
You know, direct contact with your guys would have its advantages.
Not to my guy.
This is unbelievable. Who put the cameras in this place?
Oh, who the fuck are you?
I'm the guy who does his job. You must be the other guy.
If these Chinks wanna nuke Taiwan any time in this century...
...they'd better shape up and show me 1 million dollars.
What we generally do, in this country...
...is one guy...
...brings the items...
...and the other guy...
...pays him.
No "tickee"...
...no laundry.
Go ahead, Fitz.
Cars are moving, but did you see anybody come out?
Please tell me those cars aren't empty.
I mean, Jesus fucking Christ, please tell me that those Chinamers cars aren't empty!
They didn't figure we had a navy.
Did you put a camera in the back?
Can I talk to you for a second, please?
You stupid fucking hard-on!
You fucked this whole thing up!
What the fuck did you do, you cocksucker? Let go of me!
I'm gonna rip your fucking arm off and shove it up your fucking ass!
Why don't we meet? Let me buy you an ice cream.
I'm getting on a plane unless you put Queenan on.
Queenan had a funeral to go to. This is my shift. Calm down.
Why shouldn't I get on a fucking plane, huh?
Meet up? You actually want me dead?
Look, there is a rat in your unit. That is a fact, all right?
- Where's Queenan? - He's not here.
They knew you had cameras in the building. They knew everything.
There is a leak from the inside. It's real. Man, smoke him out.
Yeah, how do we do that, Mr. Genius-Who- Didrt-Even-Graduate-From-the-Academy?
Disinform. Let it slip to SIU that you have a sealed wiretap warrant...
...for Costello's apartment. Don't tell anyone in our division, but tell SIU.
Flush it down the pipe, see if it comes out on my end.
That's what we do first. Narrow it down.
- Where the fuck is Queenan, huh? - He's not here.
You wanna meet up or you got something real, call me back.
- Changing your life radically.
Change anything. Right? Change everything.
- Right? - Yeah.
How long you been with this guy?
- My boyfriend? - Yeah.
- Four months. Almost four months. - Four months.
Do you love him?
It's a pretty serious relationship, yeah.
It's very serious.
Is he a headcase like me? I'm just curious.
No more than I am.
I know that it's a serious relationship.
I know there are ups and downs. Right?
People have doubts and problems.
Well, not problems, but doubts.
What would you do if he was standing right there and he saw us?
I would lie. Yeah, I would lie.
You know, to keep things on an even keel, right?
Right? We talked about that.
- Morning. - Good morning.
Want a French doughnut?
Yeah.
- Hey, can I lookit? - Yeah.
Sure.
- All right, we're not having this out. - What?
You don't see any pictures of where I came from.
Look, I respect who you are...
...just, you know, not in the living room.
We might have company.
- Company? - Yeah, company.
- Hey, now, why do you work for the state? - Why not? You do.
No, what you do. The degrees and all, everything you got. You're hot shit.
Yeah?
So why do you make as much as a guidance counselor?
Because I believe in public service.
So now you're gonna fuck with me? So now you're gonna be ridiculous, huh?
- No, don't start with me. Don't... - Hey.
Ah, fuck with the fucking phone! Stop it!
- The phone. - Forget the phone.
Get it. Answer it. Answer it.
This is your first phone call in the new house.
You live here now. You're a resident.
Mayor Sullivars office.
Put Colin on the phone right now.
Oh, my God. I'm sorry.
What?
I think it's a guy with...
- It's like a cancer guy. - Hello.
What the fuck is it with you and your phone, huh?
Something for work.
Hey. Nothing, nothing, nothing. It went dead. I don't know, I get...
Was that that shrink cunt that answered the phone?
Remember I told you that we were... She was gonna move in?
- Yeah. - She moved in.
- You better get organized, quick. - Hey, last time I checked, I tipped you off...
...and you're not in jail.
- Are you listening to me? - Yeah.
Do you like Little Miss Thing sucking on your cock?
Yes. Yes, I do.
So earn it.
I'm getting the feeling...
...we got a cop in my crew.
Yeah, I know, I'm kind of getting that feeling too.
He's one of yours. Inside.
Have you seen anything?
I got no access to Queenars undercover files. He and Dignam run the snitches.
- Doing my best. - Your best?
What do you think we're in, the fucking haberdashery business?
Look, Frank, if you don't relax...
If you don't relax, I can't relax. All right? Now, what I need you to do...
...get me information on the people with you last night. Your crew.
Get me social-security numbers, get me...
Get you? Give you? Who the fuck do you work for?
All right, all right. Frank, Frank, Frank. All right. I'm sorry.
If you could, please. What I need are SS numbers, DOBs...
...just all the pedigree information so I can run it on my end and we can ID the prick.
If you can get me that information...
...I can... We're gonna handle it. I can handle it.
Calm down, or you'll shoot in your pants.
I'll get you the records and whatnot.
But listen to me, son. Don't disappoint me on this...
...or some other guy will be putting their fat cock...
...up Little Miss Freud's ass.
How are you, Francis?
- My mother called me Francis. - I know she did.
And your father called you the tumor.
And what did your father call you, Charlie?
Oh, yeah, I forgot. He wasrt around.
You have a boss that has a laryngectomy?
No, no, no. That was a guy who works for me.
You're lying to me.
Not exactly.
What did you do with the real microprocessors, Frank?
Microprocessors.
Oh, yeah.
I heard the story. You arrested some Chinese government guys...
...at the border carrying some light sockets or something.
I can't wait to wipe that fucking smirk off of your face.
Wouldrt you rather wipe my ass for me?
There are certain parts of my job that I'm not gonna be able to talk to you about.
And I cannot allow you to jeopardize an ongoing investigation...
...or your life.
No, really, there are things you don't even wanna know about.
Okay, then just say that.
All right, I will.
Oh, that's the movers.
Yeah, you still wanna stay?
- Yes. - Yeah?
Come on, I'm coming! It's the worst timing.
I'm gonna get you.
If you could've, you would've.
But I guess you like to go at your own pace.
Excuse me. Got a date with some angels.
Frankie.
Frankie!
Your mother forgives me.
You take off an armored car at the mall.
What the fuck, you pay guineas in Providence?
- Fucking now I do! - What the fuck do you do?
I gotta pay Costello for him to trade me to the FBI? Because that's what he does.
FBI? What the fuck you talking about, FBI?
My God, is that French out there?
What the fuck did you just say about the FBI?
Forget what I said. I'm fucking high.
Whatever may be going on in that very fucking poor...
...very limited brain of yours, I am not gonna hurt you, all right?
- Just tell me what you fucking said. - Forget it.
I'm high. I'm fucking high. I must be high. I'd never say what you thought I said.
Fuck!
Now, what the fuck did you just fucking say?
Why do you think he never gets busted? Costello's a protected FBI informant.
He'll trade you out.
I thought I was supposed to go into shock.
I'm not in shock. It fucking hurts!
It fucking hurts!
Hey. It's me.
- What are you doing here? - Come here.
Costello's giving people up to the FBI.
- The FBI? - He is giving information to the FBI.
He's a protected fucking informant.
I mean, aren't they always trying to make it a federal case and it never gets made?
Go around the back. I'll open the door. Go on.
- Here's some ice water. - Oh, thanks. Thanks.
That's my son, Patrick.
- Goes to Notre Dame. - Oh, yeah?
My wife's asleep but she left some supper out. You want something to eat?
No. No, thanks.
Yeah, come on, man. You have some supper. We'll talk in the kitchen.
Come on.
You want some coke?
There it is.
Don't move till you're numb.
Come on. Get inside.
Boss wants your real name...
...your social and license number, your bank account numbers.
I don't have a bank account.
- I'm a cash business myself. - What's he doing, setting up IRAs?
Just fill the fucking paper in. Your real name and all your account numbers.
Then we wait here.
- You're shitting me. - No, I ain't.
Put the forms in there.
I don't know if this is how you spell "citizens."
But fuck it, you know?
No, no, no. Come here.
What, are you fucking retarded or something?
That ain't fucking right.
Are you kidding me?
Look at this. Look.
"Citizens." Look.
Billy, he said to stay here.
Yeah. I'm not sitting here without a tetanus shot.
Where the fuck are you going?
I'm not staying, all right? You can tell him I said that.
- Hey. - Hi.
- It's pouring out there. - Yeah.
Look...
...if this is inappropriate, l... - No.
No, it's not inappropriate. You're not a patient.
So you moving out or you moving in?
I've still got three weeks left on the lease.
That's me.
Yeah, I know.
- Hedging your bets? - No. No.
You have to choose.
- You have to make a... - A decision.
A decision. And, you know, you have to stick by what you choose.
- You have to... - Move in with your boyfriend?
Yes. Otherwise it's...
Oh, I know, I know. I know.
I have to say your vulnerability is really freaking me out right now.
Is it real?
I think so.
You don't have any cats.
No.
I like that.
I don't get it.
We are all convinced that Costello has at least...
...one mole inside the Special Investigations Unit.
You will investigate everybody and anybody.
Well, that's not exactly a dream job for a cop.
We looked at all possible candidates. You have an immaculate record.
Some people don't trust a guy with an immaculate record. I do.
I have an immaculate record.
How is your wedding coming along?
Great. Great. She's a doctor.
- That's outstanding. - Yeah.
Marriage is an important part of getting ahead.
Lets people know you're not a homo. Married guy is more stable.
People see the ring, think at least someone can stand him.
Ladies see the ring, they know you must have some cash and your cock must work.
Yeah, it's working. Overtime.
- I'm glad to hear that. - Thank you.
跟着信封
Be dirty, be dirty.
Yeah...
Frank. The fuck is wrong with you?
- See anything you like, Col? - I almost fucking shot you.
- You're not indulging in self-abuse, are you? - Sit down.
I hope you're not turning into one of them sob sisters wants to get caught.
You're not cracking up, are you?
- I don't crack up. - Pick a place like this...
...where any cop could see you. Jesus.
If this is such a fucking bad idea why'd you show up?
I own the place.
Why am I not fucking surprised?
- All right, lookit, I gotta tell you... - You're getting reassigned. I know.
How the fuck do you know that?
- Where'd they put you? - Hey, Frank.
I gotta find myself.
You're telling me, sonny boy.
I gotta find the guy you got in the department.
With everybody looking up their own ass and you looking for yourself...
...I put my money on nobody finds nothing.
I know, but, Frank, lookit. For me, you gotta lay low.
- Right now. - Collie...
...laying low is not what I do.
All right, fucking Big Daddy Frank. Fucking perfect.
What good am I to you if you don't listen to me?
What good am I if you don't listen?
识别疑犯
Queenan is compartmentalizing. He's splitting everything up.
He's fucking smart. You know this.
I can get the rat. You just gotta let me do it my way, Frank.
Okay.
But Colin, I hope I won't have to remind you...
...that if you don't find that cheese-eating rat bastard in your department...
...most likely, it won't be me who suffers for it.
Now, why would you have to remind me of that?
Would I be any good at what I do if I didn't fucking already know that?
Frank, you gotta trust me.
All right? Just trust me, Frank.
Hey, it fucking involves lying and I'm pretty fucking good at that. Right?
Right?
Maybe because it's always been so easy...
...for me to get cunt that I never understood jerking off in a theater.
Christ.
Who knows what's easy?
Colin, I know you'll take care of business.
Shit!
Fuck.
进行拘捕
Hey, how you doing?
Hi, Darlene, hi.
- That's it for me. - Yeah, see you.
Have a good one.
I smell a rat.
Jesus Christ.
You got a girlfriend?
No.
No, no. Why, what does that matter?
It depends.
I'm sure by now you know...
...I got an informer in my outfit.
Cop.
Staties, Boston Police Department, I'm not sure.
Jesus Christ.
Are you sure it's not the FBI?
It ain't the FBI.
Ex-wife.
Old girlfriend.
Or stupid.
That is what brings you down in this business.
Stupid, huh?
Well, I guess that leaves me out.
You know, past days, situation like this, I kill everybody.
Everybody who works for me.
Right. You know, Frank...
...I look around at your other guys...
I mean, they're all murderers, right? Right?
And I think, "Could I do murder?"
And all I can answer myself is:
"What's the difference?"
Give them up to the Almighty.
You see, that's my point, you know?
You accuse me once, I put up with it.
You accuse me twice...
...I quit.
You pressure me to fear for my life and I will put a fucking bullet in your head...
...as if you were anybody else. Okay?
You got something you wanna ask me?
Look, you're 70 years old, Frank. I'm just saying, okay?
One of your guys is gonna pop you.
- One of your guys is gonna pop you. - Yeah, yeah.
As for running drugs, what the fuck are you doing?
You don't need the money or the pain in the ass. And they will catch you.
I haven't needed the money...
...since I took Archie's milk money in the third grade.
Tell you the truth, I don't need pussy anymore, either.
But I like it.
Point I'm making here is, Bill...
...I got this rat...
...this gnawing, cheese-eating, fucking rat...
...and it brings up questions.
You know. See, Bill, like, you're the new guy.
Girlfriend...
Why don't you stay in the bar that night I got your numbers?
Social-security numbers.
- Yeah. - Everybody's fucking numbers.
Is there something that you just wanna go ahead and ask me?
Because I'll give you the fucking answer, all right?
Frank, look at me. Look at me.
I'm not the fucking rat. Okay?
I'm not the fucking rat.
Start with you agree there is a rat.
You said there is one, all right?
I base most of what I do on the idea that you're pretty good at what you do.
Sure. Sure, Will.
You, William. What would you do?
Frank, how many of these guys...
...have been with you long enough to be disgruntled?
Think about it. You don't pay much, you know.
It's almost a fucking feudal enterprise.
The question is, and this is the only question...
...who thinks that they can do what you do better than you?
The only one who could do what I do is me.
Lot of people had to die for me to be me.
You wanna be me?
I probably could be you. Yeah.
Yeah, I know that much.
But I don't wanna be you, Frank.
I don't wanna be you.
"Heavy lies the crown" sort of thing.
Yeah.
- Francis. - I'm out of here. You'll set the alarm...
- Yeah, all right. I'll see you at Christmas. - All right. Good night.
You know what I like about restaurants?
The fucking food? I don't know. What?
You learn a lot watching things eat.
There's a boat coming up Gloucester.
French will give you all the details. Don't forget.
Eat something, for Christ's sake.
In the future, I tell you to do a thing, you fucking do it. You got that?
I got it. Okay?
Excuse me...
...French, I forgot my... - Okay, Francis.
...cigarette.
Eat something.
Problem?
Yeah, I got a problem. I run rat fucks like you, okay? I don't like them.
The day you wouldn't take a promotion, let me know.
If you'd taken care of this I wouldn't be here.
- Fuck yourself, you piece of shit. - I need the identity of your undercovers.
Blow me. Not literally. Unfortunately, there's no promotion involved for you.
Fucking prick.
- Hi, captain. - Look who's here. The prom queen.
- They are not happy with me. - What do you expect?
Everybody knows you've been assigned here to find Costello's rat.
They want to find the leak as much as you do.
Like I said, two days ago, my guy damn near found out who Costello's rat is.
- But he lost him in the streets. - Really?
- Well, did he get a look at the guy? - No.
I mean, nothing? Like, I mean, anything that could help us.
No.
So you got any advice for me? Just, I mean, generally.
Costello can't do much business without coordinating with his source...
...who is here in SIU.
Follow Costello. You'll find his rat.
You're gonna be looking at my people...
...going through their bank statements, their phone calls and medical records.
Don't be surprised if they don't buy you a beer or invite you into their homes.
Let me get you a coffee.
If I wasrt with the Massachusetts State Police...
...if I did it full-time, law school...
...I'd be through it in a year.
If I wasrt a trooper.
But another city. I was thinking that.
Another city.
Another city, huh?
Yeah, well, that would be a clean slate.
I want you to know, you don't got to stay.
If we're not gonna make it...
...it's gotta be you that gets out, because I'm not capable.
I'm fucking Irish. I'll deal with something being wrong for the rest of my life.
It might not be a bad idea, you know, another city.
- Of course I know how to spot a cop. - How's that?
If he's not paying attention to us, he's a cop.
Lookit. You see that guy over there? Right over there.
Yeah.
Not paying attention to us. He's a cop.
- Okay. - You get it now, do you?
查无此人
- What about this guy? - Cop.
Hey, how you doing? What kind of dog is that?
She ignored us so she must be a cop.
She's probably the fucking police commissioner.
You can get out of here. I'm using a new crew tonight. New guys.
- I thought I was on for this. - I changed my mind. Take the night off.
Francis, we're ready for the sushi bar.
- Jimmy, bring a mop. - Out the back.
There's guys who answer the questions right...
...and there's guys that don't. - And a pail.
You're a cop.
What?
You ignored us, you're a cop.
We're guessing who cops are. You know, most good-Iooking women are cops.
Well, I'm going home, all right? He's playing with his new guys.
- See you later, all right? - See you later.
威廉·科斯提根
查无此人
He's moving something with all new guys. A whole new crew.
No, no, I can't tell you what or where. It's probably disinformation.
Just keep following him, all right? Listen, I need to see you today.
- Tomorrow. - No, no, no. Today.
- You heard nothing about drugs? - No.
Nothing about new guys? Nothing about Gloucester?
Not a thing. And I would have. That information would have come to me.
It ain't Bill.
No way, he says.
Follow Costello. You'll find his rat.
Yeah, this is Sergeant Sullivan.
I want constant surveillance on Captain Queenan, starting right now.
Good. Thank you.
Can I ask a question, sarge? Why the fuck are we following Captain Queenan?
To find out about the good Catholic life?
I have to follow every lead, however unlikely...
...however fucking painful it might be to your delicate fucking sensibilities.
Who told you I had delicate sensibilities?
- I just don't like it, sarge. Don't feel right. - I have reason to believe...
...that Captain Queenan is Costello's rat.
So just follow him and don't get made.
Sarge, we got the target coming out.
Hey. Where are you?
Look down the car.
- You got me? - Yeah, I gotcha.
Is there a reason you would have a tail?
No.
- Because I think... - Billy, I don't have a tail.
Get off at the next stop, all right? South Station. You wait there 10 minutes.
South Station. Wait 10 minutes.
沃时街344号
He just went into a building down the waterfront. 344 Wash.
You got that? 344 Wash.
Yeah, he went up to the top floor.
Building's empty. No tenants here.
He's got dope coming in. I don't know where. He...
He's getting spooky, captain.
- What? - I just saw him.
He had blood on his hands. He's lost his fucking mind.
I don't know what we're doing here, boys.
He's not including his regular guys. But I'll tell you something.
Sooner or later he's gonna find out who I am and he's gonna fucking kill me.
- I know it. He's gonna fucking kill me! - All right!
I think we got him. I think Queenars meeting with him right now.
All right, all right. Listen to me.
I'm really sorry for your trouble. I swear to God I am.
I'll get you out of this. I can't do it overnight but I'll get you out.
Yeah?
Hey, get the van. We're moving. Heavy work.
- What about the FBI? - They're compromised.
- They're what? - They're fucked.
- Yeah. - Where are you?
We've been trying to reach you. We found the rat.
Listen, we're gonna take him out. Lookit:
The address is 314 Washington Street. You got it?
All right, we'll see you there.
- What? - You were followed.
- By who? - By Costello's people.
- Impossible. - One of the cops...
...he's got on the inside tipped him. Come on. Come on.
Come on!
What the fuck is going on?
Fucking shit. Looks like Queenars meeting with all of them.
Yeah, he must be our guy.
Sarge, we gotta get him out of here. Those guys aren't fucking around.
Ah, Christ, it's too late. Let's go back up.
- Shit! - You got to get out of here!
- Take the fire escape. - What about you?
I'll be fine. But if you get made I can't protect you. Now, go!
- One of you mugs got a light? - Where's your boy?
- He's studying law at Notre Dame. - Where's your fucking boy?
- Hey! Hey! - Goddamn motherfucker!
- Fucking kill you! - Where's your fucking boy?
What the fuck was that? Did you fucking see that?
Sarge, something just came off the building.
What the fuck?
Fuck.
What do you mean, off the building?
- Something came off the fucking roof. - It's a fucking body.
We can't get a visual. Want us to get out?
We gotta get on foot if you want me to get up on this thing.
- Where were you? - What happened?
You're fucking late! Get in the van!
What do you mean, off the roof?
What's going on? I came to meet you.
- What the fuck...? - Get in the van!
I got four armed men right out front. You want us to pursue?
No, do not pursue. Stay in the car.
- Fuck. No fucking pursuit. - I need information.
What came off the roof?
- No pursuit. - That's bullshit.
Fuck this.
Fitzy! Get in the van!
Get in the fucking van! Let's go! Move!
All right. I got him.
32X to CP. We're being fired upon!
An officer is down. I repeat, an officer is down. A trooper's been shot!
Send some back...
So do you know why Queenan went into that building?
- No. - Well, a better question...
...is why the fuck were your guys following him?
I told Internal Investigations to follow Captain Queenan.
- Why? - That's Internal Investigations' business.
Fucking piece of shit!
- All right. - Hey, hey!
- Fucking bitch! - Let him go!
Cocksucker! I don't have to fucking explain anything to anybody!
I can fucking investigate anybody I want to!
- Come on! - I don't give a fuck what you think!
I got reason to believe that Queenan got killed by his fucking undercover.
That's a fucking lie.
He has fucking information in a locked file, as did Captain Queenan.
I need access to those files.
I forgot the password but if you come with me I'll give it to you.
- That's a fucking lie. - Nobody calls me a liar!
Shut up! Work with the tech guys to unlock those files.
- Dignam, take a leave of absence. - Take a leave of what?
Queenan is dead. I'm your boss now.
I don't care. I'd rather hand in my papers first.
World needs plenty of bartenders. Two weeks with pay.
Good.
- Piece of shit. - Fuck off.
- I need those codes. - No.
You want those codes.
So where the fuck were you?
Well, boss told me to go home.
Whatever. Maybe he did, maybe he didn't. But you werert at fucking home.
So where the fuck were you?
I was at the grocery store with no signal, all right?
When I got the signal, I got the call.
What the fuck do you want from me? Was I there or was I not there?
Billy. Billy.
Yeah?
You know what I thought today?
What's that?
Who didn't show up today is the rat.
Yeah?
- So? - And you never been late in your life.
When I called you...
...I made a mistake.
I gave you the wrong address...
...but you showed up at the right one...
...didn't you?
Tell me why I didn't tell nobody, huh?
Tell me why.
That cop was tough. We were excessive with the cop.
He's dead.
I'm going home.
- Your guys should not have done that. - One of us had to die.
With me it tends to be the other guy.
But Queenan. Now I got no access.
You killed the guy who had the info. Dignam's gone. Forget about him.
- He resigned. - I don't give a fuck about Dignam.
He put in his papers, Frank.
- He left. I don't know where he is. - Don't get your balls in an uproar, Collie.
That Irish pissant...
...he's so hot for me, we give him a whiff of my ass, he'll crawl right in it.
Let's give him a whiff.
- I will. - Don't worry. I'll take care of it.
Sweetheart.
You're giving me a hard-on.
Are you sure it's me?
Not all that talk about whiffing and crawling up asses?
Watch your fucking mouth.
No. You watch it.
Let me straighten you out.
I tried to call you a few times.
I know.
Listen, I can't be a friend to you.
I'm sorry.
Yeah...
...I know.
Yeah.
You called this number on a dead guy's phone.
Who are you?
So it is you.
Well, thank God you're all right. We were very worried.
Who are you?
This is Sergeant Sullivan.
I'm taking over Queenars unit.
Let me talk to Dignam to confirm it.
Staff Sergeant Dignam...
...is on a leave of absence. He's very upset.
We're all very upset.
I think the best thing would be for you to come in.
We need you to come in. Can you come in?
We'll meet...
卧底发现卡斯特罗是联邦调查局线人
Police confirm the body of the man found dead...
...in the Fenway marshes yesterday...
...is that of Timothy Delahunt, an undercover policeman for...
...the city of Boston. This was the scene yesterday...
...when Delahunt's body was found in the marshes near the Fenway.
As for who did this or why...
...that's something police are working on right now.
- I don't believe it. - What can't you believe?
I spent all fucking night dragging the poor bastard in there.
Tell me how they found him so fast.
Somebody walking a fucking dog in three feet of mud?
What kind of fucking size of dog is that?
Must have been a big fucking dog, man.
I spent all fucking night doing it, man.
I'm embarrassed.
I still don't believe he was a cop. I don't believe it.
The cops are saying he's a cop...
...so I won't look for the cop.
Are you soft, Fitz?
When I tell you to dump a body in the marsh...
...you dump him in the marsh.
Not where some guy from John Hancock goes every Thursday...
...to get a fucking blowjob!
Don't laugh!
This ain't reality TV!
Proceed.
- What? - Yeah.
You got a tail. Two cars. Not very subtle.
They're not gonna be subtle from now on. That's what I've been trying to say.
So get rid of them.
There's no need for you to go yourself, Frank.
Get rid of the fucking tail!
All right.
Fucking rats. It's wearing me thin.
Francis, it's a nation of fucking rats.
Stop, stop. Pull them off Costello. There's no need to surveil him.
- What are you saying? - I got it from an undercover.
He knows he's being followed. So let the UC take him in.
- Undercover? - Queenars guy.
He called when he found out Queenan died. I'm running him.
- You give him to me. - No, I can give you Costello's destination.
- You know where he's going? - Yes. And what he's doing.
Get rid of the tail, get Special Ops on standby.
- We'll take this prick tonight. - Let's go. Now.
All units fall back. All units fall back.
设菲尔德
It's the warehouse he owns over on Sheffield.
He's gotta have a container or a truck or something there. Go.
Load it.
Frank, how do you know you don't have a tail, huh?
Were you not in the fucking car?
Yeah, what if they took one off and they put another one on?
Load.
Go, go!
Come on, what are you waiting for?
Frank wants me to check the back. You go ahead.
- Watch your fucking back. - Move out! Go on!
Cocksuckers.
Motherfucking shit!
Motherfucking...!
Back the fuck up!
They fucking shot me.
Get down!
Come on, fucking bastards!
Fuck it.
How the fuck did this happen?
You're an FBI informant?
Are you fucking kidding me?
Grow up.
Of course I talk to the FBI.
Do they know who I am?
I never gave up anybody who wasrt going down anyway.
Nobody knows nothing.
Frank.
Frank. Frank.
Do they know about me?
I know about you, Collie.
You know I'd never give you up.
- You're like a... - What? Like a son?
To you? Is that what this is about?
All that murdering and fucking, and no sons.
Fucking rat prick!
Frank?
Yeah?
Who's this?
Gwen?
Where the hell's Frank?
Frank got shot.
Gwen, we lost Frank.
I got him!
I got Costello here!
Hey, good job, sarge.
No, it's...
For you.
- Thank you. - No. Thank you.
He's been waiting here a long time for you.
How'd you get him without the files?
Caller ID on Queenars phone.
You know that guy?
Yeah. We were classmates in the academy together.
Good to see you, trooper.
- Yeah. - Colin Sullivan. We spoke on the phone.
- Yeah. - So.
Now, how long were you undercover?
Long time.
- Long fucking time. - Yeah. Yeah.
Well, I can't even tell you the debt...
I just want you to know I'll be recommending you for the Medal of Merit.
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
That's kind of like a gold star around here, huh?
It's the highest honor we got.
Look, I just want my identity back, all right?
- That's all. - All right.
- I understand. You wanna be a cop again. - No, no.
Being a cop's not an identity. I want my identity back.
Check your computer. Go on. You'll have to excuse my behavior.
My only contact in the last six months has been a police shrink.
How's that working for you?
Is it helpful?
What are you gonna do about Costello's rat in this building?
- I'm gonna find the prick. - Yeah.
I'm gonna find him, I'm gonna arrest him.
- Good. - Anything you can do to help me...
You know, I mean, did Frank ever mention a name...? You know, anything.
Someone he was in contact with. Anything you can give me.
I'm all done being a cop, all right?
I just want my money and I wanna go home.
All right. That'll be the best thing for everybody.
Fair enough.
I just, I can't get into your file unless I have your password.
It's my name.
William Costigan Jr.
They gave it to me in case I had to explain myself to someone like you.
It's your name.
All right.
Fucking unreal, that... Well, makes a lot of sense.
Listen, Bill, I gotta run this in the other room.
This computer's getting all frigging blooey on me.
Give me two minutes. I'll have you out of here in no time.
All right, everything checks out, so let's get you paid.
删除
人事数据库，你确定删除？
记录删除
I know.
I know. I'm not... I'm not here for that, okay?
I'm not.
Listen. I've gotta give you something.
Something I need you to keep.
For me.
Okay?
- What is it? - This is for you to hold. Only you.
You open this if something happens to me or if I call you and I tell you to open it.
You're the only person I can trust, all right?
Please.
- All right. - Look, I'm sorry to even...
I'm sorry to even show up here like this, you know?
L... There's just no one else I could give it to.
There's no one else.
- I'm really sorry. - I...
You know, I have...
- I... - Whatever you have to say...
...think about it real hard, all right?
If you still wanna tell me, you tell me in two weeks, okay?
科斯提根
I was dreaming I was dead.
Death is hard. Life is much easier.
- What's this? - Open it.
- Really? - Yeah.
Really?
Yeah.
And they say that this little speck...
...is a penis.
It's a boy.
Yeah, well, one usually follows the other.
Can you still...?
威廉·科斯提根 科南特大街13号
科林·苏利文 皮克林大街20号
科斯提根 电话617-555-9180 播放
I hope I won't have to remind you...
...that if you don't find this cheese-eating rat bastard in your department...
...you can assume it won't be me who pays for it.
Now, why would you have to remind me of that?
Would l...? Would I be any good at what I do if I didn't fucking already know that?
Frank, you gotta trust me. I can get the rat.
You just gotta let me do it my way, Frank.
Just let me do it. Let me do what I do.
Hey, it fucking involves lying and I'm pretty fucking good at that. Right?
What?
- We got a cop in my crew. - Yeah, I know.
- I'm kind of getting that feeling too. - He's one of yours. Inside.
- You seen anything? - Frank.
I got no access to Queenars undercover files. He and Dignam run the snitches.
- I'm doing my... - You know what, I thought I was the liar.
Hey, I can explain that!
Costello recorded everything.
He put all the tapes in a box and kept them with his lawyer. That was his insurance.
His lawyer came to me.
Imagine that, you rat fuck.
Costello trusted me more than anyone.
Sound quality good enough? Because I was a little worried.
- What do you want? - I told you I want my identity back...
...you two-faced faggot.
- All right, where are you? - Three o'clock. Where Queenan died.
You keep your cell on.
Open the door.
Open... Didrt we already talk about this?
This is my job.
- Freeze! Get your fucking hands up! - Hey!
Put the fucking gun down!
Put the gun down, all right? I came here to talk some sense into you.
- Hands! - Just act professional.
- I can get you your money. - What did you say?
- I can get you your money. - You didn't come here to talk, all right?
- You came here to get arrested. - You got fucking tapes? Of what?
Costello was my informant. I was a rat? Fuck you! Prove it.
He was working for me. He was my informant.
Shut your fucking mouth. Come on, get up!
What is this, a citizers arrest? Blow me, all right?
Only one of us is a cop here, Bill. You understand that, Bill?
- No one knows you. - Shut the fuck up!
I'm a sergeant in the Massachusetts State Police. Who the fuck are you?
- I erased you! - You erased me, huh?
Yeah, go ahead, shoot a cop, Einstein. Watch what happens.
This bullet would go right through your fucking head!
- Watch what happens! - What, so you can get the parade, huh?
The bagpipes and bullshit? Fuck you! Fuck you, I'm fucking arresting you!
- That's the stupidest thing you could do. - Shut the fuck up!
I could give a fuck if the charges don't stick.
I'm still fucking arresting you.
Get up.
Drop your weapon and step away from Sergeant Sullivan.
I called you. You specifically. Look:
You know who I am. I'm not gonna shoot. I told you to meet me downstairs.
Put your weapon on the deck and step away from Sergeant Sullivan!
Where's Dignam? I told you to bring Dignam!
Shoot this motherfucker! Would you fucking shoot!
- Drop your weapon. We'll discuss it. - Look, he's Costello's rat, all right?
I got boxes of tapes! Evidence! Other documents proving it!
Maybe you do.
But right now I need you to drop the weapon!
I have evidence cold-linking this prick to Costello, all right?
- Would you shoot this fucking prick! - You know who I am.
- You know who I am. - Shoot this fucking prick.
I'm taking him downstairs now.
You know who I am.
Shut up.
I can't wait to see you explain this to a Suffolk County jury...
...you fucking cocksucker.
This is gonna be fucking fun.
Just fucking kill me.
I am killing you.
Did you think you were the only one he had on the inside?
Costello was gonna sell us to the FBI.
It's you and me now, you understand?
We gotta take care of each other, you understand?
Give me that.
Right. Slow. March.
I attempted to subdue Trooper Barrigan...
...at which time he drew down on me, and I was able to squeeze off one shot...
...and strike him in the head.
At that time I immediately checked the vitals...
...on both Troopers Brown and Costigan...
...and discovered that they had expired.
I just wanna go on record.
I'm recommending William Costigan for the Medal of Merit.
- Eternal rest grant unto him, O Lord. - Ready?
- And let perpetual light shine upon him. - Fold.
May he rest in peace. Amen.
May his soul and the souls...
...of all the faithful departed, through the mercy of God, rest in peace.
Amen.
Detail. Half left. Face.
Prepare to fire.
Fire.
Prepare to fire. Fire.
Detail. Half right. Face.
I'll catch up with you guys.
What about the baby?
Hi, pup.
Okay.
谢谢观赏！
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer™)